So by the time you're watching this, hopefully you have played yourself with vectors.
이걸 보실 때쯤엔 벡터를 이해하셨길 바라요
You've created your own chunks, you've put them in a data store, and you have looked at them in 2D
자신만의 청크를 만들어 데이터 스토어에 넣고 2D, 3D로
and 3D and made up your mind which of those you prefer?
검토한 후 어떤 게 더 좋은지 결정했죠
Well, that introduces you to chroma.
채도가 뭔지 알겠네요
Very easy to use.
사용하기 쉽죠
You can also try using other data stores.
다른 데이터 저장소도 시도해 볼 수 있어요
Vice is one that's very easy to use using the same kind of code.
바이스는 같은 종류의 코드를 사용하는 아주 쉬운 것 중 하나죠
It's a Facebook AI similarity search, and it's an in-memory vector data store that is even it's not
페이스북 인공지능과 비슷한 검색이고 인 메모리 벡터 데이터 저장소인데 난이도가 비슷할
even easy to the same amount of difficulty.
정도로 쉽지 않아요
It just involves changing 1 or 2 lines of what we already wrote.
이미 쓴 것의 한두 줄만 바꾸면 돼요
So that could be another exercise for you.
이것도 하나의 훈련이 될 수 있어요
Repeat this in office and you'll find it's it's trivial to do, and you will get, of course, consistent
사무실에서 반복하면 별거 아닌 걸 알게 될 겁니다 OpenAI 엠비딩을 사용한다면
results if you're using OpenAI embeddings.
일관된 결과를 얻을 수 있어요
Uh, so, uh, it's worth pointing out that what we've just experienced is the very best of long chain
이걸 짚고 넘어가야 할 것 같아요 방금 우리가 경험한 건 긴 사슬 중 가장 좋은 경험이었어요
in that we were able to accomplish a lot in literally just two lines of code.
말 그대로 코드 두 줄로 많은 걸 성취할 수 있었죠
There was the line when we said embeddings equals OpenAI embeddings, and that was immediately giving
삽입이 OpenAI 삽입과 같다고 한 줄이 있었는데 그건 곧바로 OpenAI
us access to OpenAI's API to use for calculating embedding vectors.
API 사용에 액세스 권한을 주어 삽입 벡터를 계산할 수 있게 해줬죠
Um, and then there was just that single line where we created our chroma database.
그리고 한 줄로 채도 데이터베이스를 만들었어요
We said chroma dot from documents.
서류에서 채도점을 썼어요
And you remember we passed in three things, documents, which in our case were in fact chunks of documents.
세 가지를 통과시켰죠 문서예요 우리 경우엔 서류 뭉치였죠
Embeddings, which are the OpenAI embeddings and the database name is the directory that it used.
OpenAI 엠버딩스, 데이터베이스 이름은 사용된 디렉터리예요
And we could have put in any name we wanted.
어떤 이름이라도 넣을 수 있었어요 Put it up Put up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it Put it up Put it
And I chose vector DB, but you can put in whatever name you wish.
벡터 DB를 선택했지만 어떤 이름이든 put을 수 있어요
The.
그요
It's worth pointing out that we created these vectors for each chunk from our original, uh, text that
우리가 읽은 원래 텍스트에서 각각의 덩어리를 위해 벡터를 만들었다는 걸 강조할 가치가
we read in.
있어요
We could equally well have put in documents there.
문서를 넣을 수도 있었어요 Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it
We could have instead created vectors for entire documents instead of for chunks.
덩어리가 아닌 전체 문서에 대한 벡터를 만들 수도 있었어요
And you can try that.
여러분도 해 보세요
Try replacing the word chunks with documents and see what you get.
get 을 문서로 바꿔치기해 보세요
Of course, there'll be fewer of them, and you can see whether they are as separated out in the same
물론 숫자는 더 적겠지만요 제 추측대로 각 칸이 얼마나 나뉘어
way I'm guessing that they will be.
있는지 볼 수 있어요
So with that, we are finally ready to bring this together and build our Rag pipeline.
이제 이걸 하나로 합쳐서 래그 파이프라인을 만들 거예요
Our Rag solution.
우리 헝겊 용액이에요
And at this point, I'm hoping all of the concepts are very clear in your mind.
지금은 모든 콘셉트가 명확히 이해되셨길 바라요
Next time we're going to again see the power of Lang Chain to be able to stitch together a full solution
다음엔 랭 체인의 힘을 보죠 코드 몇 줄로 전체 솔루션을
just with a few lines of code, including a conversation chain and memory, which are some of the things
엮을 수 있습니다 대화 체인과 메모리를 포함해서요 랭 체인이 아주 잘
that Lang Chain handles very nicely.
다루는 거죠
And we'll be able to have question and answer session demonstrating expert knowledge of the space.
질의응답 시간을 가질 수 있을 겁니다 이 공간에 대한 전문가의 지식을 보여줄 수 있죠
So that's a big milestone for us.
저희에겐 큰 이정표예요
It's rag coming together and it's happening in the next session.
다음 세션에서 래그가 완성될 거예요